Howard McClusky Collection
Howard McClusky Collection
- Miscellaneous writings
  - MS-35: The Community Approach to Adult Education, reprinted from the University of Michigan School of Education, Bulletin XV, March, 1944 (Box 7)
  - MS-36: Dissemination of Child Development Knowledge through a Program of Adult Education and Community Action, in Child Development, Vol. 19, No.1 and 2, March - June, 1948 (Box 7)
  - MS-37: Marriage and the Family, reprinted from Social Forces: Vol. 19, No.2, co-authored with Alvin Zander, October 1940 (Box 7)
  - MS-38: Mary Swanson - Teacher, reprinted from Educational Leadership, March 1946; description of satisfaction and dissatisfaction of teacher Mary Swanson by her students (Box 7)
  - MS-39: An Experiment on the Influence of Preliminary Skimming on Reading, undated (Box 7)
  - MS-40: The promise and challenge of community development, November 10, 1958 (Box 7)
  - MS-41: Tools for Democracy: Reasons for discouragement, November 22, 1954 (Box 7)
  - MS-42: An Experimental Comparison of Two Methods of Correcting the Outcome of an Exam, undated (Box 7)
  - MS-43: Phase of a larger problem, probably, August 31, 1960 (Box 8)
  - MS-44: The Information Self-Help Approach to Community Development, undated (Box 8)
  - MS-45: Continuing Education for Children, Youth and Adults, undated (Box 8)
  - MS-46: Educational Self Help Approach to Community Development, undated (Box 8)
  - MS-47: Lecture/paper notes on three characteristics, undated (Box 8)
  - MS-48: The Adult as Learner, undated (Box 8)
  - MS-49: Report on Study of Advisory Groups, undated; first draft, partial (Box 8)
  - MS-50: The Influence of Different Degrees of Meaningful Background on Reading, undated (Box 8)
  - MS-51: Inter-University Conference on the Dissemination and Use of Research Findings About Child and Human Development, December 4, 1945 (Box 8)
  - MS-52: The Community Adult Education Unit of the Extension Service, August 5, 1948; no author is indicated but likely McClusky, based on style of writing and that he was the head of the unit on which this writing is based (Box 8)
  - MS-53: School Community Relations, undated; second draft (Box 8)
  - MS-54: The Teaching Situations Test, undated (Box 8)
  - MS-55: The Experimental Use of Comparative Cultures, undated (Box 8)
  - MS-56: Counseling and Adult Education, undated (Box 8)
  - MS-57: Instructional Programs in the Adult Education Approach to Community Development - A Progress Report, co-authored by Roger Hiemstra, November 11, 1968 (Box 8)
  - MS-58: The Course of the Life-Span: A Proposed Basis for a Differential Psychology of the Adult Years, March 19, 1959; paper presented at a meeting of Professors of Adult Education, Madison, WI (Box 8)
  - MS-59: The Status of Youth in Our Culture, undated (Box 8)
  - MS-60: "One of the Great Teachers of Our Generation" in The Reader's Digest, 1952 (Box 8)
  - MS-61: Suggested Outline for "The Michigan Citizen's Role in Planning", undated (Box 8)
  - MS-62: The Need For Coming together, undated (Box 8)
  - MS-63: Advancement of Specialization, undated (Box 8)
  - MS-65: The community in council, Adult Leadership, May, 1956 (Box 8)
  - MS-66: "The School in the Community", undated; fragments (Box 8)
  - MS-68: Adult education, 1953 or 1954 (Box 8)
  - MS-69: Coordinating Community-Wide Bodies, 1955 (Box 8)
  - MS-70: Comments on Dr. Murphy's Paper: Counselor Biases and How They Affect the Client, undated (Box 8)
  - MS-71: Postwar Education, 1945[?] (Box 8)
  - MS-72: Counseling the 'Tween Age, 1945-1946 (Box 8)
  - MS-73: Suggested Criteria and Procedures for the Selection of Communities, February 23, 1946 (Box 8)
  - MS-74: Community Problems, May 17, 1944 (Box 8)
  - MS-75: Problems of Smaller Business: The Importance of Planning and Team Work, November 9, 1944 (Box 8)
  - MS-76: A Review of a book by Kenneth D. Norberg American Democracy and Secondary Education, 1944 or 1945 (Box 8)
  - MS-77: Presentation, Chicago Recreation Commission on Youth and Community Recreation, Sherman Hotel, November 22, 1944 (Box 8)
  - MS-78: Give Rural Youth a Chance, or, Some Problems and Proposals for Rural Youth, February 1944 (Box 8)
  - MS-80: Some Suggestions for the Effective Presentation of Material, 1943 or 1944 (Box 8)
  - MS-81: Education in Work Book on Education, White House Conference on Aging, January, 1971 (Box 8)
  - MS-82: The Secondary School at War, High School Principals Banquet, December 3, 1942 (Box 8)
  - MS-83: Community Coordination for Adult Education, 1942 or 1943 (Box 8)
  - MS-84: American Youth and the Present Crisis, May 13, 1941; paper presented at the Seventh Conference on Education and the Exceptional Child (Box 8)
  - MS-84.1: Panel presentation at the Jefferson Intermediate School, August 31, 1960 (Box 8)
  - MS-85: Mobilizing the Community for Adult Education, April 29, 1939 (Box 8)
  - MS-85.1: Community development – a new look, April 20, 1961 (Box 8)
  - MS-87: Supervisors of Student Teaching National Association, 1940 (Box 8)
  - MS-88: An Age for Greatness: The Secondary School at War, undated (Box 8)
  - MS-89.1: Where we are... Where are we going?, March 30, 1967 (Box 8)
  - MS-89.2: Continuing and adult education – a new challenge to higher education, October 27, 1966 (Box 8)
  - MS-90.1: Course in community organization, September 22, 1965 (Box 9)
  - MS-91: Counseling in Adult Education, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-92.1: Book review by Howard McClusky of Science and Freedom by Lyman Bryson, 1947 (Box 9)
  - MS-93.1: Notes, formation of Dexter educational community forum, August 18, 1948 (Box 9)
  - MS-94: Boy Scouts of America, 32nd annual meeting, St. Paul, MN, May 15-16, 1942 (Box 9)
  - MS-95: Education: A background paper for the 1971 White House Conference on Aging, September, 1970 (Box 9)
  - MS-96: Organizing a State Program for Youth, April 1945 (Box 9)
  - MS-97: Education for the Aging, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-1002: The Course of the Life Span: A Proposed Basis for a Differential Psychology of the Adult Years, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-30: The Experimental Use of Comparative Cultures, in The University of Michigan School of Education Bulletin Volume 5, Number 7, April 1934 (Box 9)
  - MS-101: An Approach to a Differential Psychology of the Adult Potential, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-102: Designs for Learning, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-103: Education and Aging, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-105.1: Statement on participation of rural people in the war, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-105.1: Participation of youth groups in civilian defense activities in local communities, 1941 (Box 9)
  - MS-106: Continuing Education for Alumni in American Alumni Council News, December, 1954 (Box 9)
  - MS-107: Adult, Continuing, and Community Education: The Shape and Promise of the Field, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-109.1: The legacy of the AEA-USA, May 8, 1982 (Box 9)
  - MS-109.2: "My Philosophy of Community," by Howard McClusky, 1947 (Box 9)
  - MS-110: The Changing concept of the Laboratory in Teacher-Preparation, February 1941; paper, presumably presented to National Association of Supervisors of Student Teaching (Box 9)
  - MS-111: Contributions to the general domain of adult and continuing education, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-112: When should we go on our own? How to help the adolescent break away and be himself, September 1936 (Box 9)
  - MS-113: Post War Counseling for Tween-Age Youth, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-113.1: Lecture topics on Mental Hygiene of Adolescence, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-113.3: Community self help in Michigan, July 1, 1946 (Box 9)
  - MS-114: Adult Education at the University of Michigan, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-115: Community Influences and Adult Learning, in Adult Education, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-116: Key Issues in Public School Adult Education Today, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-119: Last lecture of a series on the mental hygiene of adolescents, March 22, 1935 (Box 9)
  - MS-120: It’s Happening Here!, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-121: The Community of Generations: A Proposed Goal and Content for the Education of Persons in Later Years, 1978 (Box 9)
  - MS-122: Community Problems and Their Management: A Study of Learners' Perceptions with Implications for Adult Education, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-123: Some specific purposes of a Community Council, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-124: Education for Decision-Making, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-125: Miscellaneous notes, March 1964 (Box 9)
  - MS-126: Education, Aging and the Long Tomorrow, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-127: The Role of the Congregation, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-128: The Massive Fact -- Pupil Parent Relations, July 9, 1958 (Box 9)
  - MS-129: Lectures Assigned to McClusky, 1938-1939 (Box 9)
  - MS-129.1: Call for community responsibility, Detroit Youth Conference, January 28, 1949 (Box 9)
  - MS-130: Adult Education at the University Georgia, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-131: What's Ahead in Education, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-132: The negative suggestion effect of the false statement in the True-False test, March 1934 (Box 9)
  - MS-133: Summary Remarks and Interpretations, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-133.1: Planning for healthy communities, September 16-17, 1948 (Box 9)
  - MS-134: Six lectures on the Mental Hygiene of Adolescence University of Michigan Broadcasting Service Over WJR, 1934-1935 (Box 9)
  - MS-135: The Theory of Margin and supportive material, April 17, 1969 (Box 9)
  - MS-135.1: Group techniques, October 18, 1952 (Box 9)
  - MS-136: Development of Junior High School Idea, 1924 (Box 9)
  - MS-136.1: Commencement address, Monroe County Senior Adult Education Program, May 31, 1981 (Box 9)
  - MS-137: Plans for writing, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-138: The Department of Community Adult Education, undated; developed by McClusky (Box 9)
  - MS-139: Ideas for Community Development Chapter, undated (Box 9)
  - MS-140.1: Adult education and the learning society, October 1965 (Box 9)
  - MS-140.2: Adult education for citizenship, October, 1965 (Box 10)
  - MS-141: Adult Non-formal Learning NIE Contract Proposal, Summer, 1979; section by McClusky (Box 10)
  - MS-142: Guidance, speech given in Evanston, August 4, 1937 (Box 10)
  - MS-143: Youth and the home, speech given in Detroit, November 3, 1937 (Box 10)
  - MS-144: Continuing Education for Senior Citizens: Rationale and Introduction, circa 1969 (Box 10)
  - MS-146: Methods and strategies in reaching and teaching older adults, Dallas, Texas, September 30, 1976 (Box 10)
  - MS-147: Notes from McClusky on an adult counseling project, Grand Rapids, Michigan, January 31-February 1, 1947 (Box 10)
  - MS-148: Speech notes on Master Law of Life, Blackburn College, October 31, 1936 (Box 10)
  - MS-149: Work Paper on Adult Education (Confidential and for discussion only), 1959 (Box 10)
  - MS-149.1: The child in a changing world, June 23, 1936 (Box 10)
  - MS-150: Marks of a healthy personality, Muncie, Indiana, December 9, 1950 (Box 10)
  - MS-151: Education and the present crisis, Land O’ Lakes, Wisconsin, December 3, 1950 (Box 10)
  - MS-152: Life centered education in a child centered community, Evanston, Illinois, April 1, 1938 (Box 10)
  - MS-153: What can personnel workers contribute to the defense of Democracy? Atlantic City, New Jersey, February 29, 1941 (Box 10)
  - MS-154: Does America have a youth problem? Ann Arbor, Michigan, January 17, 1946 (Box 10)
  - MS-155: The Volunteer and the Community Dimension, undated (Box 10)
  - MS-156: Mental Hygiene of Childhood and Adolescence, Basic Reading List (Box 10)
  - MS-160: Adult Education Schooling and the Learning Society, undated (Box 10)
  - MS-162: Education Under Democracy - Capitalism with special reference to the United States of America, December 28, 1934 (Box 10)
  - MS-163: Psychological approach to the adaptation of the New Media of Communication in Education, February 26, 1935 (Box 10)
  - MS-164: List of references, arranged chronologically, undated (Box 10)
  - MS-165: In Defense of Teachers (Box 10)
  - MS-166: Mental Hygiene of Adolescence: The Adolescent, his future and orientation to his world, March 22, 1935; sixth lecture of a series broadcast over WJR (Box 10)
  - MS-170: Notes on Iowa State Planning Committee US? State Committee of B.A.E, July 22-August 23, 1941 (Box 10)
  - MS-171: An experimental comparison of reading the original and digest versions of an article, November, 1940 (Box 10)
  - MS-172: Notes on Stability in an Age of Uncertainty, July 28, 1946 (Box 10)
  - MS-174: Notes on setting up a cooperative TUA-AYC Youth Project, undated (Box 10)
  - MS-175: Handwritten notes on Steps in setting up Rural Youth Program, undated (Box 10)
  - MS-176: Henry Taylor, advice on Rural Project, undated (Box 10)
  - MS-177: Questions by McClusky concerning youth, 1940 (Box 10)
  - MS-178: Notes on meeting, undated (Box 10)
  - MS-179: Bureau of Studies and Training in Community Adult Education, undated (Box 10)
  - MS-180: The teacher and the small community, undated (Box 10)
  - MS-181: Notes written at Lexington, Kentucky, November 13, 1944 (Box 10)
  - MS-182: Notes from Adult Education Conference, February 8, 1947 (Box 10)
  - MS-183: Guidance Workshop, October 22, 1963 (Box 10)
  - MS-186: Some points and notes on Long Range Goals, undated (Box 10)
  - MS-187: Summary of Park Community Council Meeting, October 1, 1964 (Box 10)
  - MS-189: Education for Aging, undated (Box 10)
  - MS-191: Intergenerational Relations in Educational and Contributive Perspective, undated (Box 10)
  - MS-193: Re-discovering the Person: New Frontiers in Physical Education, April 5, 1968 (Box 10)
  - MS-194: The Educative Community (Provisional), April 4, 1977 (Box 10)
  - MS-195: Lecture notes for H510, June 1-June 11, 1981 (Box 10)
  - MS-200: Education and Persons in the Later Years (PLUS): Objectives, Outline, Plan and Guidelines, undated; author not indicated but probably McClusky (Box 10)
  - MS-206: Adult Learner and Strategies for Instructors, Madonna College (notes), February 23, 1980 (Box 10)
  - MS-207: State Conference of Adult and Continuing Education Association of Nebraska (Notes), April 27, 1973 (Box 10)
  - MS-209: Psychology of Adult and Continuing Education Studies, October 18, 1979 (Box 10)
  - MS-210: Aging and the Caring Community, October 25, 1979 (Box 10)
  - MS-211: Telephone Network - history of Community Education, October, 1979 (Box 10)
  - MS-216: Notes on Humanities and Aging Project, September 10, 1974 (Box 10)
  - MS-219: The Adult as Lifelong Learner: Some implications for instructions in Higher Education, undated (Box 10)
  - MS-226: Best present ever, in U.S. Jaycee Action, December, 1957 (Box 10)
  - MS-228: How to Bring About Institutional Change, 1949 or 1950 (Box 10)
  - MS-229: On Changing an Institution, undated (Box 10)
  - MS-232: New Factors in Youth Adjustment, July 10, 1952 (Box 10)
  - MS-233: A New Look at Selected Areas of Adult Education, December 14, 1960 (Box 10)
  - MS-235: Organizing for Community Improvement, undated (Box 11)
  - MS-244: Review of manuscript by Leslie L. Chisholm, "Guiding Youth in the Modern Secondary School", July 24, 1944 (Box 11)
  - MS-247: Role of the School in Improving Mental Health in the Community -- State University Teachers College, Cortland, New York, July 30, 1956 (Box 11)
  - MS-248: Later Years, May 12, 1983 (Box 11)
  - MS-249: The School as a Community Centre, University of Toronto, April 3, 1945 (Box 11)
  - MS-252: Education for Leadership in Social Responsibility, undated (Box 11)
  - MS-256: Load over Power Equals Margin, It is the Ratio Which Counts, undated (Box 11)
  - MS-257: Adult Dimensions of Life Long Learning: Reflections on the Future of the Educational Enterprise, undated (Box 11)
  - MS-259: An Experimental Comparison of the New Type Test and the Term Paper, undated (Box 11)
  - MS-260: Residential Propinquity and Marriage in Branch County Michigan, undated (Box 11)
  - MS-261: The Responsibility of Higher Education for Religious and Moral Values, undated (Box 11)
  - MS-262: An Educational Service for Michigan Communities, May 5, 1955 (Box 11)
  - MS-266: Adult Education as Public Relations, undated (Box 11)
  - MS-268: An application of Mental Hygiene Principles to the Problems of Adolescence, October 20, 1947 (Box 11)
  - MS-269: A Philosophy of Work Experience, undated (Box 11)
  - MS-272: Adult Education: Its promise and Relevance, undated (Box 11)
  - MS-274: The Information Self Help Approach to Community Development, undated (Box 11)
  - MS-276: The Pre-Adolescent and Family Background of Adolescence, Ann Arbor, Michigan, November 9, 1934; first lecture of a series on adolescence, broadcast over WJR (Box 11)
  - MS-277: Notes on increasing the margin by increasing the capacity for enjoyment of experiences, undated (Box 11)
  - MS-279: Community Planning for Nutrition - Summary of Discussion, May 26, 1941; introduction by McClusky (Box 11)
  - MS-286: An Approach to a Differential Psychology of the Adult Potential, reproduced from Adult Learning and Instruction, Eric Clearing House on Adult Education, AEA, 1970 (Box 11)
  - MS-288: Field of Research and Training in Adult Education, co-authored with Jenkins and Zanders, undated (Box 11)
  - MS-295: Memo to Hon. Charles D. Perkins, Chairman, General Labor Subcommittee on H.R. 10143, A bill for Adult Basic Education, February 15, 1962 (Box 11)
  - MS-297: The Role of the Local Church, December, 1978 (Box 11)
  - MS-298: American Youth and the Present Crisis, April 14, 1942 (Box 11)
  - MS-304: Some Current Trends in Community Organization, March, 1946 (Box 11)
  - MS-305: Rediscovering the Community - Some New Frontiers for Physical Education, undated (Box 11)
  - MS-313: What research says about the change with age in mental ability and cognitive performance with implications for learning in the later years, undated (Box 11)
  - MS-314: Communities learn from one another, 1952 (Box 11)
  - MS-317: A Study of the "Talk Contacts" of Adolescent Pupils with their teachers co-authored with Ernest H. Chappelle, undated (Box 11)
  - MS-325: Creating Wholesome Attitudes in Youth, October 5, 1930 (Box 11)
  - MS-327: Parent-Child Relationship at Adolescence, WJR, University of Michigan, November 15, 1932 (Box 11)
  - MS-329: Community Approach to the Education of the Undereducated, undated (Box 11)
  - MS-333: National Organization Section, notes on operation, very rough draft (Box 11)
  - MS-334: The role of education in achieving the older person’s potential, undated (Box 11)
  - MS-336: Comments on Dr. Murphy’s paper, "Counselor biases as they affect the client", 1959 (Box 11)
  - MS-337: Adult education, conference on education, Haven Hill, December 11-13, 1959 (Box 11)
  - MS-338: The changing concept of the laboratory school, American Youth Commission, undated (Box 11)
  - MS-340: Collection of poetry, prose, and musings by McClusky (Box 11)
  - MS-341: Collection of letters and other material about McClusky (Box 11)
  - MS-342: Musings, reflections, and remembrances about McClusky from family members (Box 11)
- Tapes
  Dates given may apply to one or both sides of tape. All are audiocassettes.
  - AT1: Dr. McClusky’s young adult speech, Buffalo, NY, November 6, 1959 (Box 12)
  - AT2: Side one: HYM on need to relate importance of group discussion and religion viewed at a limit to growing and maturity; side two: 2nd seminar on adult learning – continues discussion of adult maturity, November 5, 1979 (Box 12)
  - AT3: Side one: 2nd seminar continued – adult learning and adult materials; side two: need to relate, importance of group discussion, religion viewed as a limit to growth and maturity, November 5, 1979 (Box 12)
  - AT4: Side one: McClusky, ACE lecture, Introduction by Berlin – agencies responsible for adult education; side two: research, the 1980 Adult Education Handbook Series, impressions regarding the future, November 10, 1978 (Box 12)
  - AT5: McClusky sessions 1-4 (Box 12)
  - AT6: HYM’s ACE lecture, Adult Learning, Schools of thought in Psychology, September 23, 1979 (Box 12)
  - AT7: Interview with McClusky, University of Michigan Students, on the history and background of adult education, 1968 (Box 12)
  - AT8: Side one: McClusky: History of AEA founding in 1951; side two: McClusky interview with M. Day and E. Thurman, March 26, 1979; October, 1978 (Box 12)
  - AT9: Side one (only): St. Louis, Interview with McClusky (Box 12)
  - AT10: Side one: part 2 in HYM’s adult learning seminar on what is adulthood, maturity, Erikson; side two: HYM explores his schematic for understand maturity and autonomy (Box 12)
  - AT11: Howard McClusky interview by Roger Hiemstra on contributions, June 28, 1979 (Box 12)
  - AT12: Edith McClusky Zinn, Howard’s daughter, October 18, 1989 (Box 12)
  - AT13: Edith McClusky Zinn, Howard’s daughter, October 18, 1989 (Box 12)
  - AT14: Interview with McClusky and Freire, elderly education, St. Louis (Box 12)
  - AT15: McClusky interview (both sides) (Box 12)
  - AT16: Side one: McClusky, ACE lecture, introduction by Berlin, agencies responsible for adult education; side two: research, the 1980 adult education handbook series, impressions on the future, November 11, 1978 (Box 12)
  - AT17: HYM, education and lifelong learning development (Box 12)
  - AT18: Dr. McClusky; Boone (Box 12)
  - AT19: Dr. McClusky’s birthday party, March 15, 1980 (Box 12)
  - AT20: Howard McClusky interview on history of AEA, interviewed by Mike Day (both sides), March 26, 1979 (Box 12)
  - AT21: Side one: Howard McClusky, history of AEA’s founding, 1959; side two: interview with Mike Day and E. Thurman, March 26, 1979; October, 1978 (Box 12)
  - AT22: Side one: McClusky, July 3, 1979, discussion of aims of adult education, interview with Mike Day; side two: seminar with Nerry (Box 12)
  - AT23: Howard Y. McClusky from 1974 to 1982, by Joel Olah (both sides), April 6, 1985 (Box 12)
  - AT24: Interview of McClusky, No. 1 (both sides) (Box 12)
  - AT25: Interview of McClusky, No. 2 (both sides) (Box 12)
  - AT26: Interview of McClusky, No. 3 (both sides) (Box 12)
  - AT27: Interview of McClusky, No. 4 (both sides) (Box 12)
  - AT28: Remembrances of HYM by Blue Carstenson, part 1 (both sides), March 29, 1985 (Box 12)
  - AT29: Remembrances of HYM by Blue Carstenson, part 2 (both sides), March 29, 1985 (Box 12)
  - AT30: John McClusky (Howard’s son) interview, part 1 (both sides), August 14, 1990 (Box 12)
  - AT31: John McClusky (Howard’s son) interview, part 2 (both sides), August 14, 1990 (Box 12)
  - AT32: John McClusky (Howard’s son) interview, part 3 (both sides), August 14, 1990 (Box 12)
  - AT33: Howard McClusky’s speech at Paul Bergevin retirement dinner, April, 1972 (Box 12)
  - AT34: Dr. Howard McClusky, Winterset, April 3, 1969 (Box 12)
  - AT35: Howard Yale McClusky, “A Reminiscence,” George E. Parks of Union Academy (both sides), includes written comments from Helen (Box 12)
  - AT36: David Peterson’s presentation at the NAEC, Milwaukee, November 7, 1985 (Box 12)
  - AT37: Roger Hiemstra’s speech on Howard at the Milwaukee NAEC, November 8, 1985 (Box 12)
  - AT38: H501, McClusky’s January 12 lecture in the first session (both sides), circa 1970 (Box 12)
  - AT39: H501, first 45 minutes from McClusky’s January 12 lecture; rest is the beginning of the January 19 lecture (both sides), circa 1970 (Box 12)
  - AT40: H501, Roger Hiemstra’s presentation on Program Development and Evaluation (Box 12)
  - AT41: H551, various students, part 1 (both sides), November 20, 1965 (Box 12)
  - AT42: H551, various students, part 2 (both sides), November 20, 1965 (Box 12)
  - AT43: Jaycee community development seminar, part 1 (Box 12)
  - AT44: Jaycee community development seminar, part 2 (Box 12)
  - AT45: Jaycee community development seminar, part 3 (Box 12)
  - AT46: Reflections on McClusky by several students, part 1 (both sides), June 8, 1985 (Box 12)
  - AT47: Reflections on McClusky by several students, part two, June 8, 1985 (Box 12)